Harry Potter: A History Of Magic is a documentary film directed by Jude Ho.
A thrilling journey through legends, belief and folklore, this film goes behind the scenes with the British Library as they search to
tell that story through objects in their collection, in an ambitious new exhibition: Harry Potter: A History Of Magic.
Rowling, who is lending unseen manuscripts, drawings and drafts from her private archives (which will sit alongside treasures from the British Library, as well as original drafts and drawings from Jim Kay)
talks about some of the personal items she has lent to the exhibition and gives new insight into her writing, looking at some of the objects from the exhibition that have fired her imagination.
Narrator, played by Imelda Staunton.
Herself, played by J.K. Rowling.
Himself, played by David Thewlis.
Himself, played by Warwick Davis.
Herself, played by Evanna Lynch.
Himself, played by Mark Williams.
In the fictional universe of Harry Potter, magic is depicted as a
supernatural force that overrides the laws of nature.
In humans, magical ability is inborn and is usually inherited.
Most children of magical parents are magical themselves.
These are called Half-Bloods/Purebloods and are common.
Some children of "Muggle" (non-magical) parents also display magical abilities.
These are called Muggleborns and these are uncommon.
Children who are born to wizard parents but cannot perform magic
are called Squibs although these are very rare.
Known Squibs in Harry Potter are Mrs Figg and Argus Filch.
Rowling, the creator of Harry Potter, based many magical elements in her
fictional universe on real-world mythology and folklore.
She has described this derivation as "a way of giving texture to the world".
The magic of Harry Potter was the subject of a 2017 British
Library exhibition and an accompanying documentary.
The exhibition, entitled Harry Potter: A History of Magic, was the first at the
British Library to be based on a single series by a living author.
The film explores themes of magic, sorcery, wizard,
psychotronic filmmaking, artefacts.
The tone is intense.